<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> <game> <title>Great White Flight</title> <release-date>18 August, 2015</release-date> <website>http://www.greatwhiteflight.com/</website> <press-can-request-copy>TRUE</press-can-request-copy> <platforms> <platform> <name>Android</name> <link>http://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ikonicgames.greatwhiteflight</link> </platform> </platforms> <prices> <price> <currency>All Currencies - </currency> <value>Free</value> </price> </prices> <description> Markee the Shark is a Great White who was living happily, munching away on all the Tasty Fish. That is until the Tasty Fish hired the Pirate Parrots to take him out! These Pirate Parrots are a little loopy and are now wreaking havoc on Markee's ocean home from their Pirate Planes. Markee must defend his home before the Pirate Parrots succeed in their assigned mission! </description> <history> Great White Flight originated from a prototype created in a game development challenge where Erin made 9 games in 12 weeks. You can find that prototype here: http://www.ikonicgames.com/weeklys/Week05.html. Originally created with HaxeFlixel, I later converted to Unity3d to create the game and partnered with Dustin Hyden of http://www.letspoly.com/ to give it a clean low poly look. Orignally scheduled for a realise that would coincide with Shark Week, I had to postpone due to moving out of my rental house, moving all of my stuff to my parent's and starting a year long journey through South America(her blog can be found here: http://www.vachaventures.com). </history> <features> <feature>Addictive gameplay that is fun to pick up and rewarding to master!</feature> <feature>Tight Controls for extraordinary shark acrobatics!</feature> <feature>Global Leaderboards. Beat your friends scores!</feature> <feature>Pirate Parrots who will stop at nothing to destroy your ocean home!</feature> <feature>Delicious Fish! What shark doesn't love fish?</feature> </features> <trailers> <trailer> <name>Trailer</name> <youtube>z_akkJL-umg</youtube> </trailer> </trailers> <credits> <credit> <person>Erin Gunn</person> <role>Programmer, Designer</role> </credit> <credit> <person>Dustin Hyden</person> <role>Art</role> </credit> </credits> </game>