<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ikonic Games</title>
    <description>Ikonic Games @IkonicGames is a one-man game development &#39;studio&#39;, currently based somewhere in South America.  I like making games that everyone can play and nobody wants to put down.</description>
    <link>http://ikonicgames.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://ikonicgames.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 12:30:06 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 12:30:06 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Ikonic Games Website</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new Ikonic Games website!  The new design will allow me to deliver much higher quality content and showcase my games that will be available for play and licensing.  Here is a quick outline of my goals with this relaunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-blog&quot;&gt;The Blog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the developers that I follow, I follow because of the content that they share with the game development community.  They are often posting “back stage” glimpses of their design processes as well as tutorials on various tools.  Without these insights I would not be the developer I am today.  I’ll be offering these same kinds of insights for other devs in hopes of giving back to a community that has already given so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-games&quot;&gt;The Games&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, my games will exclusively target HTML5 mobile and desktop browsers, leaning toward mobile.  This is a market that is still relatively new, and while HTML5 games are current “fad”, the games that I am looking to produce will target a niche market that I plan to gain a solid foothold in.  Additionally, having such a narrow focus will make it easier to demonstrate and develop my expertise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After establishing myself in the HTML5 market, I will branch out into others as time permits.  The most likely order will be flash(hopefully), mobile and then desktop.  Flash is listed first because, if I use the correct framework, it is likely the easiest platform to simultaneously target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, have a look around at the new site and if you have any feedback or comments, &lt;strong&gt;leave them below or shoot me a message on any of the social media profiles linked in the sidebar to the right&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 18:59:59 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ikonicgames.com/blog/jekyll/update/2015/10/21/Intro.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ikonicgames.com/blog/jekyll/update/2015/10/21/Intro.html</guid>
        
        <category>template</category>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 18:59:59 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ikonicgames.com/blog/jekyll/update/2015/10/21/000-Template.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ikonicgames.com/blog/jekyll/update/2015/10/21/000-Template.html</guid>
        
        <category>template</category>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Tom&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &amp;#39;Hi, Tom&amp;#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-help&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s dedicated Help repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 11:16:54 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ikonicgames.com/blog/jekyll/update/2015/10/21/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ikonicgames.com/blog/jekyll/update/2015/10/21/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        <category>testing</category>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
